Edward L. Bernays Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part I: Miscellany, 1896-1963 (Box I:496-509)
  Newspaper clippings, notes, memoranda, press releases, photographs, desk diaries, notebooks, a ledger, research files, a biographical file, lecture notes, student memorabilia, printed matter, and financial material.
  - Newspaper clippings (Box I:496)
    - 1919-1963, undated
    - Undated (Box I:497)
  - Notes, memoranda, press releases, photographs, and surveys (Box I:498)
    - 1913-1961
    - Undated (Box I:499)
    - Undated (Box I:500)
  - Desk diaries, 1936-1942
  - Child's composition book, 1935
  - Notebook, undated
  - Accounts payable ledger, 1938
  - Guest register, undated
  - Research material (Box I:501)
    - Psychoanalysis
    - Morale in wartime
    - Public relations
    - Propaganda (Box I:502)
    - Big business
  - Biographical material (Box I:503)
  - Propaganda Analysis, Oct. 1937-Sept. 1939
  - New York University, New York, N.Y., lecture notes, 1949-1950
  - Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y., laboratory reports, 1909-1910 (Box I:504)
  - Notes and drawings, 1896-1906
  - Legal documents
  - Estate papers of Ely Bernays (Box I:505)
    - 1897-1934
    - 1933-1957 (Box I:506)
  - Printed matter (Box I:507)
    - 1904-1931
    - 1932-1942 (Box I:508)
    - 1943-1962, undated (Box I:509)
- Part I: Scrapbooks, 1918-1956 (Box I:510-723)
  - Client, Institution, and Organization File, 1919-1952 (Box I:510-700)
    Newspaper clippings, magazine articles, pamphlets, invitations, press releases, programs, and awards.
    Arranged alphabetically by subject and therein chronologically.
    - A. G. Spalding and Brothers See Containers I:657-661, Spalding and Brothers, A.G. (Box I:510-511)
    - America Self Contained Committee, 1933-1935, (2 vols.)
    - American Economic Foundation, 1935, (2 vols.) (Box I:512-513)
    - American Institute of Baking, 1938 (Box I:514)
    - Associated Bakers of America, 1938 (Box I:515)
    - American Nurses Association (Box I:516)
      - 1945-1946
      - 1947-1948 (Box I:517)
      - 1948 (Box I:518)
    - American Tobacco Co. (Box I:519-522)
      - 1929, (4 vols.)
      - 1931, (2 vols.) (Box I:523-524)
    - American Whaling Information Service, 1939 (Box I:525)
    - Best Foods, Inc., 1926-1927 (Box I:526)
    - Council of Better Business Bureaus (Box I:527)
      - 1949
      - 1951 (Box I:528)
    - Camillus Cutlery Co., 1950 (Box I:529)
    - Cheney Brothers (Box I:530)
      - 1923
      - 1924, (4 vols.) (Box I:531-534)
      - 1924-1926 (Box I:535)
      - 1925 (Box I:536)
      - 1926-1927, (3 vols.) (Box I:537-539)
      - Silk Association of America (Velvet Group), 1925 (Box I:540)
      - Velvet Fashion Service Bureau, 1925 (Box I:541)
    - Color Fashion Bureau, 1934, (4 vols.) (Box I:542-545)
    - Columbian Rope Co., 1947-1948 (Box I:546)
    - Commission on Inquiry on National Policy in International Relations, 1934 (Box I:547)
    - Commission on Inquiry on Public Service Personnel, 1933-1934 (Box I:548)
    - Dartnell Corp., 1939 (Box I:549)
    - Dodge Brothers, 1928 (Box I:550)
    - Eastern Millinery Association, 1925-1929 (Box I:551)
    - Edible Gelatin Manufacturers Association, 1926-1927 (Box I:552)
    - Fish and Seafood Institute, 1935, (3 vols.) (Box I:553-555)
    - National Franklin Committee (Box I:556)
      - 1942-1943
      - 1943 (Box I:557)
    - Thomas P. Henry Co., type book, 1928 (Box I:558)
    - French Industrial Exposition, Paris, France (Box I:559)
      - 1924
      - 1925, (7 vols.) (Box I:560-566)
    - General Baking Co., 1925 (Box I:567)
    - Goldman, Eric Frederic, 1948 (Box I:568)
    - Great Northern Railway Co., 1935 (Box I:569)
    - Hampshire House, 1931 (Box I:570)
    - Hart, Schaffner & Marx, 1925, (3 vols.) (Box I:571-573)
    - Hillside Homes Housing Development, 1933 (Box I:574)
    - Independent Oil Companies of America, 1933 (Box I:575)
    - Dixie Cup Co., 1933-1934, (2 vols.) (Box I:576-577)
    - First International Artificial Flower Show, undated (Box I:578)
    - Loft, Inc., 1936 (Box I:579)
    - McCall's (Box I:580)
      - 1946
      - 1949 (Box I:581)
      - 1949, Eleanor Roosevelt, memoirs (Box I:582)
    - Mack Trucks, Inc. (Box I:583)
      - 1950
      - 1950-1951 (Box I:584)
      - 1951, (2 vols.) (Box I:585-586)
      - 1952 (Box I:587)
    - Madison Square Garden Corp., 1935 (Box I:588)
    - Miscellany, 1943-1946 (Box I:589)
    - Miller, Banks L., 1935 (Box I:590)
    - Millinery Fashion Bureau, 1940 (Box I:591)
    - Nash-Kelvinator Corp. (Box I:592-602)
      - 1936, (11 vols.)
      - 1937, (6 vols.) (Box I:603-608)
    - National Association of Curled Hair Manufacturers, undated (Box I:609)
    - National Association of Glue Manufacturers, 1945 (Box I:610)
    - National Broadcasting Co., 1939-1940 (Box I:611)
    - National Council of American Importers and Traders, 1921 (Box I:612)
    - National Electronic Radio and Television Exposition, 1946 (Box I:613)
    - Television Authority, 1949-1950 (Box I:614)
    - New York, N.Y., tourism, undated (Box I:615)
    - New York Real Estate Securities Exchange, 1929 (Box I:616)
    - Pearl Associates, 1939 (Box I:617)
    - Pennsylvania Optometric Association, 1942, (2 vols.) (Box I:618-619)
    - Philco Radio and Television Corp. (Box I:620-623)
      - 1934, (4 vols.)
      - 1935, (2 vols.) (Box I:624-625)
      - 1935-1936 (Box I:626)
      - 1936, (3 vols.) (Box I:627-629)
      - 1936-1937 (Box I:630)
    - Procter & Gamble Co. (Box I:631)
      - Drene Shampoo
        - 1941
        - 1941-1944 (Box I:632)
        - 1942 (Box I:633)
        - 1944-1945 (Box I:634)
        - 1945, (2 vols.) (Box I:635-636)
      - General (Box I:637)
        - 1925-1927
        - 1932 (Box I:638)
        - 1952 (Box I:639)
      - Ivory Soap, 1941 (Box I:640)
      - National Glycerine Service, 1925 (Box I:641)
      - Soap sculpture contest (Box I:642-643)
        - 1926, (2 vols.)
        - 1928-1929, (2 vols.) (Box I:644-645)
        - 1929 (Box I:646)
        - 1930 (Box I:647)
        - 1931, (2 vols.) (Box I:648-649)
        - 1933, (2 vols.) (Box I:650-651)
        - 1933-1934 (Box I:652)
        - 1934 (Box I:653)
    - Pullman Co., 1938 (Box I:654)
    - Radio Institute of the Audible Arts, 1935 (Box I:655)
    - Sherry-Netherlands Hotel, New York, N.Y., 1922-1923 (Box I:656)
    - Spalding and Brothers, A.G. (Box I:657)
      - 1938
      - 1939 (Box I:658)
      - 1940, (3 vols.) (Box I:659-661)
    - Starret Investing Co., 1935 (Box I:662)
    - Steward and Co., 1929 (Box I:663)
    - Tanners' Council of America (Box I:664)
      - 1945
      - 1945-1946 (Box I:665)
      - 1946 (Box I:666)
      - 1946-1947, National Foot Health Council (Box I:667)
      - 1946-1947 (Box I:668)
    - Trunk Luggage and Leather Goods Manufacturers, 1927 (Box I:669)
    - United Fruit Co. (Box I:670)
      - Middle America by Charles Morrow Wilson
        - 1942-1944
        - 1942-1947 (Box I:671)
      - Middle America Information Bureau (Box I:672-675)
        - 1943, (4 vols.)
        - 1944, (2 vols.) (Box I:676-677)
        - 1944-1945 (Box I:678)
        - 1945 (Box I:679)
        - 1946, (3 vols.) (Box I:680-682)
        - 1946-1948 (Box I:683)
        - 1947 (Box I:684)
        - 1948 (Box I:685)
    - Veterans of Foreign Wars of the United States, Ladies Auxiliary, 1938 (Box I:686)
    - Victory Book campaign, 1942-1943, (3 vols.) (Box I:687-689)
    - Erwin Wasey & Co., undated (Box I:690)
    - Woods, Arthur, 1919, (3 vols.) (Box I:691-693)
    - Child Research Clinic of the Woods Schools (Box I:694)
      - 1934-1938
      - 1939-1941 (Box I:695)
    - House of Worth (Box I:696)
      - 1926-1927
      - 1928-1929 (Box I:697)
    - Samples of printed matter (Box I:698-699)
      - 1928
      - Undated (Box I:700)
  - Personal, 1918-1956 (Box I:701-723)
    Newspaper clippings, magazine articles, photographs, pamphlets, invitations, press releases, programs, and awards.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - 1918-1942 (Box I:701)
    - 1919-1930 (Box I:702)
    - 1927-1932 (Box I:703)
    - 1930-1933 (Box I:704)
    - 1932-1935 (Box I:705)
    - 1933-1936 (Box I:706)
    - 1935 (Box I:707)
    - 1936-1938 (Box I:708)
    - 1936-1939 (Box I:709)
    - 1937-1945 (Box I:710)
    - 1938-1945 (Box I:711)
    - 1940-1942, Speak Up for Democracy (Box I:712)
    - 1942-1943 (Box I:713)
    - 1942-1943, "The Future of Private Enterprise in the Post-War World" (Box I:714)
    - 1944 (Box I:715)
    - 1945, Take Your Place at the Peace Table (Box I:716)
    - 1945-1947 (Box I:717)
    - 1948-1949 (Box I:718)
    - 1950 (Box I:719)
    - 1951 (Box I:720)
    - 1953 (Box I:721)
    - 1954-1955 (Box I:722)
    - 1956 (Box I:723)
- Part I: Oversize, 1915-1945 (Box I:OV 1-24)
  Oversize scrapbooks.
  Organized and described separately.
  - Artificial Flower Style Service, 1929, (7 vols.) (Box I:OV 1-OV 7)
  - Ballets russes See Container I:OV 9, Diaghileff Ballets Russes
  - Cosmopolitan, "The Pace That Kills," 1921 (Box I:OV 8)
  - Diaghileff Ballets Russes (Box I:OV 9)
    - 1915
    - 1915-1916 (Box I:OV 10)
    - 1916, (4 vols.) (Box I:OV 11-OV 14)
  - Drene Shampoo (Box I:OV 15-OV 16)
    - 1941, (2 vols.)
    - 1943 (Box I:OV 17)
    - 1943-1944 (Box I:OV 18)
    - 1944 (Box I:OV 19)
    - 1944-1945 (Box I:OV 20)
  - Nash-Kelvinator Corp., 1936 (Box I:OV 21)
  - Procter & Gamble Co., Ivory Soap, 1941, (2 vols.) (Box I:OV 22-OV 23)
  - United Fruit Co., Middle America Information Bureau, 1942-1943 (Box I:OV 24)
- Part II: Family Correspondence, 1890-1972 (Box II:1)
  Incoming and outgoing correspondence between Bernays and family members.
  - 1890-1972, undated, (2 folders) (Box II:1)
- Part II: General Correspondence, 1911-1975 (Box II:1-14)
  Incoming and outgoing correspondence with accompanying enclosures, memoranda and reports.
  - 1911-1938, (3 folders) (Box II:1)
  - 1940-1965, (6 folders) (Box II:2)
  - 1966-1968, (4 folders) (Box II:3)
  - 1968-1969, (4 folders) (Box II:4)
  - 1970, (4 folders) (Box II:5)
  - 1970-1971, (3 folders) (Box II:6)
  - 1971, (8 folders) (Box II:7-8)
  - 1972, (8 folders) (Box II:9-10)
  - 1973, (4 folders) (Box II:11)
  - 1973-1974, (4 folders) (Box II:12)
  - 1974-1975, undated, (3 folders) (Box II:13)
  - Miscellaneous photocopied material, 1911-1972, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box II:14)
- Part II: Client, Institution, and Organization File, 1930-1970 (Box II:15-22)
  Correspondence, memoranda, printed matter, reports and surveys, clippings, photographs, lists, press releases, and notes.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of person, organization, or subject.
  - "Free Clients," 1969-1970, (2 folders) (Box II:15)
  - Gantron reports and releases, 1947
  - International cigars, 1932-1933, (2 folders)
  - Mental health, circa 1969, (4 folders) (Box II:16)
  - Procter & Gamble Co., beautiful hands contest, 1930, (2 folders)
  - Railroad account
  - Scudamore, Rene
  - Town Affiliation Association, 1969 (Box II:17)
  - United States Information Agency, 1969, (8 folders); (3 folders) (Box II:18, Box II:19)
  - West Valley College, Campbell, Calif., circa 1968-1970, (3 folders)
  - Surveys and questionnaires (Box II:20)
    - "Comments on First Questionnaire," 1925-1927
    - White, Percival, 1936-1937, (2 folders)
    - News censorship, 1954
    - Television commercials, 1954, (6 folders) (Box II:21-22)
- Part II: Speeches and Writings File, 1925-1975 (Box II:23)
  Manuscript drafts, research notes, and printed copies.
  - Rough drafts, research notes, and offprints, 1925-1975, undated, (6 folders) (Box II:23)
- Part II: Edward L. Bernays' Foundation File, 1968-1975 (Box II:24-51)
  Essay entries for the Anglo-American International Relations Contest in 1969 and general correspondence, press releases, financial papers and newspaper clippings.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material.
  - Anglo-American International Relations Contest, 1969 (Box II:24-28)
    - General correspondence, publicity, etc., (19 folders)
    - American and British inquiries, (7 folders) (Box II:29-31)
    - American essay entries, (35 folders) (Box II:32-41)
    - British essay entries, (25 folders) (Box II:42-50)
  - General correspondence, clippings, etc., 1968-1975, (9 folders) (Box II:51)
- Part II: Doris Fleischman Bernays File, 1900-1975 (Box II:52)
  Correspondence, biographical material, drafts and printed copies of speeches and writings, research notes, and newspaper clippings.
  - Correspondence, biographical material, research notes, rough drafts of speeches and articles, offprints of articles, and newspaper clippings, 1900-1975, (12 folders) (Box II:52)
- Part II: Miscellany, 1890-1979 (Box II:53-60)
  Correspondence, memoranda, notes, newspaper clippings, reports and studies, printed matter, bills and receipts, cards and invitations, grammar school and college notebooks and related memorabilia, photographs, lists, and bibliographies.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of person or organization, topic, or type of material.
  - Boston University, Boston, Mass., class survey, 1969 (Box II:53)
  - Case for Reappraisal
  - Class notes and memorabilia, 1900-1910, (2 folders)
  - Committee of Eighty, eightieth birthday celebration
  - Committee on Public Information, 1919 (Box II:54)
  - Crime and Correction Committee, 1969
  - Emergency Committee to Save Homes for Family Life in Cambridge, Mass., 1969
  - Freud, Sigmund, 1907-1971
  - Handicapped persons' facilities, 1969-1970
  - Lists and bibliographies, 1958, 1966-1970, undated, (5 folders)
  - Motion Picture Association, 1949-1964
  - Bills, receipts, identification cards, and miscellaneous items, (2 folders) (Box II:55)
  - Cards, invitations, lists, and memoranda, (4 folders)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1890-1979, (5 folders) (Box II:56)
  - Photographs
  - Printed matter (Box II:57-58)
  - Reports and memoranda (Box II:59)
  - World Health Organization (Box II:60)
  - Yaffe, Bertram
  - Your Future in Public Relations (1961)
- Part III: Family Papers, 1831-1993 (Box III:1-6)
  Correspondence primarily between Bernays and family members. Other papers include a diary, financial and legal items, speeches, writings, notes, genealogical material, newspaper clippings, and printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material and therein alphabetically by name of family member.
  - Correspondence (Box III:1)
    - Bernays, Anne F. (daughter) and Doris (daughter), 1938-1950, undated
    - Bernays, Doris Fleischman (wife), 1915, 1923-1945, undated
    - Bernays, Ely (father) and Anna Freud (mother), 1895-1912, 1922-1923, undated
    - Bernays, Peter M. (nephew), 1947, 1981-1990, undated
    - Freud, Anna (cousin), 1958-1962
    - Freud, Ernst L. (cousin), 1957-1966
    - Freud, Harry (cousin), 1937-1941, 1958
    - Freud, Martin (cousin), 1923, 1939-1940, 1958
    - Freud, Sigmund (uncle), 1919-1931
    - Freud, Walter (cousin), 1958-1990
    - Held, Doris Bernays (daughter) and family, 1967-1972, 1986, undated
    - Heller, Judith (sister) and Victor (brother-in-law), 1923, 1933-1938, 1958, 1964-1966
    - Wiener, Walter F. (nephew), 1984-1993
    - Other relatives, 1942, 1954-1991, undated
  - Other papers
    - Bernays, Anna Freud (mother)
      - Article about Sigmund Freud, undated
      - Miscellany, 1904, 1918, 1928, 1939-1955, undated
    - Bernays, Anne F. (daughter), 1965-1989, undated
    - Bernays, Doris Fleischman (Box III:2)
      - Biographical file, 1970-1977, undated
      - Clippings, 1923-1989, undated
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1914-1979, undated
        - Get well, 1956, undated, (4 folders)
        - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1927-1928
      - Diary, undated
      - Legal papers, 1980
      - Miscellany, 1915, 1947, 1970-1988, undated
      - Research material (Box III:3)
        - Education, undated
        - Education and women, 1949-1950, undated
        - Miscellaneous, 1949, undated
      - Speech file, 1956-1966, 1972, undated
      - Writings
        - Articles
          - Correspondence, 1948-1949
          - Texts and related material, 1915-1920, 1949, 1977, undated
        - Book reviews, 1968-1976, undated
        - Books
          - Outline of Careers for Women, 1928-1929
          - A Wife Is Many Women For additional material see Container III:2, Roosevelt, Eleanor
            - Correspondence
              - Bernays, Doris Fleischman, 1955-1958, (2 folders)
              - Bernays, Edward L., 1955-1957, 1965, (3 folders)
            - Draft, undated, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box III:4)
            - General, 1955-1956, undated
            - Printed matter, 1955-1963, undated, (3 folders)
          - Miscellany, 1941, 1957-1961, undated, (3 folders)
    - Bernays, Ely
      - Correspondence, 1883, 1898-1903, 1910-1923, undated
      - Miscellany, 1890-1899, 1911-1923, undated, (2 folders) (Box III:5)
    - Bernays, Hella Freud (sister), 1963, 1974-1979, 1985
    - Fleischman, Harriet (mother-in-law), 1943, 1950-1953, undated
    - Freud, Anna (cousin), 1971
    - Freud, Harry (cousin), 1938
    - Freud, Jacob (grandfather), 1866, 1892
    - Freud, Martha Bernays (aunt), 1909, undated
    - Freud, Sigmund
      - Article, 1930
      - Miscellany, 1936, 1958-1962, 1970-1989, undated
      - Movie, 1961-1963 For additional material see Container III:1, Freud, Ernst L.
    - Freud-Marlé, Lilly (cousin)
      - Draft of book about Sigmund Freud, undated, (4 folders)
      - Miscellany, 1931-1938, 1969-1979, undated
    - Freud papers, sale by the Bernays family, 1962-1963, 1990-1991 (Box III:6)
    - Genealogical material, 1962-1965, 1975-1988, undated
    - Held, Doris Bernays, and family, 1972-1979
    - Legal papers, 1990-1993
    - Miscellany, 1831, 1856, 1876, 1895, 1925-1934, 1964-1991, undated
    - Wedding of Edward L. Bernays and Doris E. Fleischman, 1922
- Part III: General Correspondence, 1905-1994 (Box III:6-26)
  Correspondence and memoranda, including attachments, between Bernays and friends, acquaintances, clients, and the public relating to his personal and professional activities.
  - 1905-1932, (6 folders) (Box III:6)
  - 1933-1945, (9 folders) (Box III:7)
  - 1946
    - Jan.-July, (2 folders)
    - Aug.-Dec. (Box III:8)
  - 1947-1963, (9 folders)
  - 1964, (4 folders) (Box III:9)
  - 1965
    - Jan.-Nov., (5 folders)
    - Dec. (Box III:10)
  - 1966
    - Jan.-Aug., (7 folders)
    - Sept.-Dec., (2 folders) (Box III:11)
  - 1967, (8 folders)
  - 1968-1974, (10 folders) (Box III:12)
  - 1975
    - Jan.-June
    - July-Dec., (2 folders) (Box III:13)
  - 1976, (7 folders)
  - 1977-1978, (7 folders) (Box III:14)
  - 1979
    - Jan.-Oct., (3 folders)
    - Nov.-Dec. (Box III:15)
  - 1980, (3 folders)
  - 1981
    - Jan.-Aug., (3 folders)
    - Sept.-Dec., (2 folders) (Box III:16)
  - 1982, (6 folders)
  - 1983, (5 folders) (Box III:17)
  - 1984
    - Jan.-Mar.
    - Apr.-Dec., (7 folders) (Box III:18)
  - 1985 (Box III:19)
    - Jan.-July, (7 folders)
    - Aug.-Dec., (5 folders) (Box III:20)
  - 1986
    - Jan.-Feb., (2 folders)
    - Mar.-Aug., (7 folders) (Box III:21)
    - Sept.-Dec., (4 folders) (Box III:22)
  - 1987
    - Jan.-July, (4 folders)
    - Aug.-Dec., (3 folders) (Box III:23)
  - 1988
    - Jan.-Sept., (5 folders)
    - Oct.-Dec., (2 folders) (Box III:24)
  - 1989, (3 folders)
  - 1990
    - Jan.-June, (2 folders)
    - July-Dec., (5 folders) (Box III:25)
  - 1991, (4 folders)
  - 1992-1994, undated, (5 folders) (Box III:26)
- Part III: Client, Institution, and Organization File, 1913-1992 (Box III:26-40)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes of meetings, newsletters, background information, surveys, notes, financial and legal papers, press releases, photographs, newspaper clippings, and printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of person or organization, topic, or type of material and therein chronologically.
  - American Optometric Association, 1943, 1962, 1969, undated (Box III:26)
  - American Tobacco Co.
    - General, 1927-1935, 1992, undated
    - Green campaign, 1930-1934, (2 folders)
  - Ballets russes See Container III:30, Diaghileff Ballets Russes
  - Bernays public relations counseling letter
    - Correspondence
      - 1959, (3 folders)
      - 1960-1961, undated (Box III:27)
    - General, 1959-1960, 1972, undated, (2 folders)
    - Proposal and legal papers, 1959, 1971-72, undated
    - Questionnaires, 1972
  - Book Publishers Research Institute
    - England, 1930
    - General 1930-1931, (2 folders)
    - Price cutting, 1930
    - Reading habits of outstanding Americans, 1930 (Box III:28)
    - Women, 1930
    - Word contest, 1930
  - Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen
    - Correspondence, 1963-1966, undated, (2 folders)
    - General, 1963-1964, undated, (4 folders)
  - Cartier, 1918-1924, undated, (3 folders) (Box III:29)
  - Charles River Hospital, Cambridge, Mass., 1980
  - Cheney Style Service, 1924
  - Columbia Broadcasting Co., 1975
  - Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 1925, 1947, 1957-1960, undated
  - Columbian Rope Co., Auburn, N.Y., 1947, undated
  - Commerce Department, 1974-1977, undated, (2 folders)
  - Committee for the Study of Mankind, 1957-1958
  - Committee on Foreign Affairs, 1966-1968, undated, (5 folders) (Box III:30)
  - Diaghileff Ballets Russes, 1915-1916, 1939, undated
  - F. A. Stahl and Associates Architects, 1967
  - Farmers' Campaign for Monetary Reform, 1931-1932, undated
  - Ferenczi, Sandor, 1925-1928
  - Gelatin committee bulletins, 1925-1926, (2 folders)
  - General Electric Co., Pittsfield, Mass., union members, 1961 (Box III:31)
  - Harken, Dwight E., 1976
  - Health, Education, and Welfare, Department of, 1976, undated
  - Henry Clay and Bock and Co., cigar plant, 1932-1933, undated
  - Howell, James, 1990
  - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1958, 1968
  - International Psychoanalytical Foundation, 1925-1926, undated
  - Light's Golden Jubilee
    - General, 1929, 1986, undated, (2 folders)
    - Photographs, undated, (2 folders)
    - Scrapbook, 1929, undated, (3 folders) (Box III:32)
  - Lipkin, Arthur Bennett, 1936, 1944, 1955-1968, undated, (5 folders)
  - Massachusetts Bar Association, 1972-1976, (2 folders) (Box III:33)
  - Massachusetts Bay United Fund, 1968-1969
  - Massachusetts Department of Mental Health, 1972-1976, undated
  - Miscellany, 1921-1928, 1936-1937, 1949, 1964, undated
  - Mutual Benefit Life Insurance Co., 1913, 1924-1928, 1941-1944, 1964, undated
  - National Association of Manufacturers, 1947
  - National Board of Fire Underwriters, 1941
  - National Committee for an Adequate Overseas Information Program, 1954
  - National Committee to Study and Resolve the Problems of Aging Americans, undated
  - New York World's Fair, New York, N.Y., 1939
  - Pace University, New York, N.Y., 1983
  - Philco Radio and Television Corp., undated
  - Photographs, undated
  - Press releases, 1923-1924, 1939, 1949, 1966-1968, undated (Box III:34)
  - Process Research, Inc., 1971
  - Procter & Gamble Co.
    - General, 1949-1967
    - Soap sculpture contest, undated, (2 folders)
  - Retail Millinery Association, undated
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1958
  - Social Science Research Council, undated
  - State Bank of Long Beach, Long Beach, N.Y., 1957
  - State Department, 1971-1977, undated
  - Suffolk University, Boston, Mass., 1962-1965
  - Surveys
    - American business and life, undated
    - American movies overseas, 1958
    - Newspapers, top ten, 1961, 1969-1974, undated, (4 folders) (Box III:35)
    - "What the British Think of Us"
      - Correspondence
        - 1957, (2 folders)
        - 1958
          - Jan.-Feb., (3 folders)
          - Mar.-Dec., (7 folders) (Box III:36)
        - 1959, undated
      - Form letter orders, 1957-1958, (3 folders) (Box III:37)
      - General, 1939-1967
      - Report, 1958
    - Women's City Club of Boston, Mass., 1966-1973, undated, (2 folders)
  - Truman, Harry S., 1945
  - United Fruit Co.